二零二一年中考英语。
一，听五个句子，选择与所听内容相符的图片，并在答题卡的相应位置将
其字母序号涂黑。
每个句子读两遍。
1. It's a quarter past four now.
Let's go home.
It's a quarter past four now.
2. In spring festival, people stay up and eat dumplings for good luck.
3. was one of the greatest inventions in ancient China.
4. The Great Wall is the pride of Chinese people.
5. Don't make any noise.
Keep quiet. They are reading now.
2. 6. How soon will he come back to school?
二，听五个句子，分别选择其相应的应答语，并。
在答题卡的相应位置将其字母序号涂黑。
每个句子读两遍。
7. How far is it from your home to the factory?
8. Have you read today's newspaper?
9. Try your best and work harder from now on.
10. The traffic makes too much noise and I can't sleep well at night.
The traffic makes too much noise and I can't sleep well at night.
三、听五段对话，根据其内容及个体的问题，选择正确选项，并在答题卡
的相应位置将其字母序号涂黑。
每段对话读两遍。
noise 12. How much
13. much is of 14.
is your birthday?
Well, the day comes after Teacher's Day.
It's easy to remember.
14. May I borrow the novel that you're reading, Sorry, it's not mine.
Maria wants to take it back soon and lend it to Jane.
15. Did Peter go to the cinema alone?
No, he's too young to go there alone.
Mike went there with him.
四，听一篇短文，根据短文内容和所提问题选择正确答案，并在答题卡的
相应位置将其字母序号涂黑。
短文。
Every year, many people get hurt or lose their lives in traffic accidents.
17. How can we keep safe when we are walking on the street?
Here is some advice for you.
First, we must obey the traffic rules.
We can cross the street only when we see the green walk sign.
We had better not run across the street to catch the bus, which is leaving soon.
Just wait. Second,
before we cross the street, we must stop and look both ways, look left, look right,
and look left again.
New traffic laws say that if people cross the street when the light is red, they can
be fined as much as 50 yuan.
Third, we must never play on the street.
Last, it's good to help children and old people cross the street.
All of us should be very careful when we are walking on the street.
First, we must obey the traffic rules.
We can cross the street only when we see the green walk sign.
the We We had better not run across the street to catch the bus, which is leaving
soon. Just wait.
Second, before we cross the street, we must stop and look both ways, look left, look
right, and look left again.
New traffic laws say that if people cross the street when the light is red, they can
be fined as much as 50 yuan.
Third, we must never play on the street.
Last, it's good to help children and old people cross the street.
All of us should be very careful when we are walking on the street.
听力二：听一篇短文，根据所听到的短文内容。
填写表格，答案书写在答题卡第二卷各小题规定的位置。
Read Craig Kilburger was born in in 1982.
短文读两遍。
At the age of 12, he read a in the Toronto Star newspaper about a poor boy.
The boy was killed because he fought for the rights of children.
And from reading the story, he knew many children in some countries couldn't go to
school. So he and his friends started The Free the Children.
The organization helps to develop the education in Kenya, India, China, and some
other countries. Today they have built more than 700 schools and school rooms in
these countries. They have also provided clean water, health care to more than 1
million people all over the world.
Craig Kilburger was born in Canada in 1982.
At the age of he read a story in the Toronto Star newspaper about a poor boy.
The boy was killed because he fought for the rights of children.
And from reading the story, he knew many children in some countries couldn't go to
school. So he and his friends started The Free the Children.
The organization helps to develop the education in Kenya, India, China, and some
other countries. Today they have built more than 700 schools and school rooms in
these countries. They have also provided clean water,
health care to more than 1 million people all over the world.
听力考试到此结束。
同学们，请继续答题。